holacracy.org 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy – Holacracy

Your privacy is very important to us. At HolacracyOne we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. 
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site. 

HolacracyOne, LLC (“HolacracyOne” or “We”) operates several websites including holacracy.org. It is HolacracyOne’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### **Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, HolacracyOne collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Our purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how visitors use our website. From time to time, we may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of our website.

HolacracyOne also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses from for logged in users and visitors in an effort to fight spam or analyze the source of traffic errors. We only disclose IP addresses under the same circumstances that we use and disclose personally-identifying information as described below.

### **Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to HolacracyOne’s websites choose to interact with HolacracyOne in ways that require us to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that we gather depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, for visitors who wish to receive HolacracyOne updates via email, we collect their emails.  In each case, we collect such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with HolacracyOne. We don’t disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Aside from IP addresses, visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### **Aggregated Statistics**

HolacracyOne may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, we may monitor the most popular pages on the holacracy.org site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. We may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, we don’t disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### **Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

HolacracyOne discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on HolacracyOne’s behalf or to provide services available at HolacracyOne’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those internal partners, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using our websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. We will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to our internal partners, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, we disclose potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of HolacracyOne, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an HolacracyOne website and have supplied your email address, we may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with HolacracyOne and our products. We take all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### **Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of our websites, and their website access preferences. HolacracyOne visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using HolacracyOne’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of our websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### **Business Transfers**

If HolacracyOne, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that HolacracyOne goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of HolacracyOne may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### **Ads**

HolacracyOne doesn’t display any ads directly on its websites, however we may sometimes use other channels (e.g. social media networks) to display ads to our website visitors. Ads appearing on any of those channels may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by HolacracyOne and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### **Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and at our sole discretion. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
